It is very easy to purchase Hey Fox Health Insurance policy.
Open any dot website and enter
any health insurance
policy as per your need.  He will give you five or six
health insurance plans of your choice
and you will select one from them
and the health insurance
policy will be issued to you.  But
purchasing the right health insurance policy is a very
difficult task.  And there are three reasons that
prevent you from purchasing the right health insurance policy.  The first option among them is
multiple options.  There
are so many health insurance policies available.  You do
not understand which is the right health
insurance policy for you.  And the
second biggest reason is
discounts.  By giving online and offline discounts of 5%-10%,
you
purchase such a health insurance policy
which is of no use to you when the time comes
and the third one is rebate, some agent
comes to you and tempts you with 10, 15, 20% discount
and you
purchase any health insurance policy on his advice and you get to
know the reality when you go to the hospital but
in today's video I have tried to
give you a complete solution to your problem and you can
choose the right health insurance policy for yourself and your family
and the definition of right always remains the same for me
which gives you
a hassle free claim settlement when you go to the hospital.  So in today's
video, I have brought to you a
comparison of six health insurance plans.  These six
health insurance plans are available to you within 2026.  If you
choose any of these, I think
this could be the best health insurance plan for you.
Watch the video till the end.  You
can also share it with friends and relatives.  If you have come to
Insurance Service for the first time, then subscribe to Insurance Service
and press the bell icon.
[Music]
A slide has appeared on my screen that
exposes the insurance company.   That means
fundamentals.  What does the insurance company
say?  If you choose
your health insurance policy based only on this slide,
then I claim that that
policy will be the best policy for you.  Let us see
what the claim settlement ratio
says?  What is Incident Claim Ratio
?  How are the network hospitals?  And
most importantly, how is the reimbursement claim process
?  It happens a lot.  So
I have taken HDFCR, here I am going to compare these six health insurance plans ICC LBR Tata AIG
nivpa SBI General Insurance Company and Care
Health Insurance.
So ICC LBA has a claim settlement
ratio of 97%, HDFCO 98%, Tata AIG 95, Neeva
BPA 92, SBI 97 and Care Health Insurance has
maintained its claim settlement ratio with 93%.  Incured Claim Ratio
which is the latest.  Currently IRDA has
published it in December 2025.
82% ICC is low with its annual report.
HDFCR has 85%.  Tata EIG is 76%.  1%
is Nivapa.  SBI is at 82% followed by
Care Health Insurance with 65%.  Fixed Claim
Ratio is a very important aspect.
Although claim settlement ratio
is also important.  But the incurred claim ratio
actually tells the position of the insurance company
that how much premium the insurance company has
taken from the market and
how much amount of claims it has settled against it.  That is,
if ₹100 has come as
premium and against that a claim of ₹80 has been
given, then the incurred claim ratio is 80%.
And any income claim ratio between 80 to 90 will be
called ideal because the insurance company receives a
lot of claims and the insurance company has to
make its margin and profit only from 5 or 10%.
If any insurance company is not maintaining the incurred claim ratio
at a genuine level, then understand that an
alarming situation may arise there.  So ICC LB
82% is an ideal incurred claim ratio.   This is a
very good claim ratio, this is an included claim
ratio.  85% HDFCGO id is IDL.  76% Tata AI
and 61% Niva BP which is blow average.
Below average means that it
falls below a standard.  82% SBI Alpha and 65%
Care Health Insurance.  We will
talk about network hospitals.  This is also an
important aspect.  But network
hospitals can change, they can be less
or more.  You must have heard
that this particular hospital's
tie-up with that insurance company has ended.
Similar tie-ups also end
and continue to be formed in the future.
15,000 near the hospitalyard.
14,000 are with HDFCO.  10,000 are
with Tata AIG.  Neeva BPA has 11,000.
20,000 are with SBI General Insurance Company.
And Care Health Insurance
has a network of 9,000 hospitals.  Now
a very important aspect, a very
important point for a health insurance policy is the
reimbursement claim
process.  Look Fox, if I talk about cashless claim, then
its tax and the entire process is
almost the same for all the insurance companies.
You have to go to the hospital.  You have to
submit your policy there.  You have to
submit your documents and the entire
process is done by the hospital and it directly
talks to the insurance company.  You do
n't have much of a role in it.  You have a
role in the reimbursement claim process.
Because the reimbursement claim process is either done by
you yourself or by your agent.
So here is the ICC LBD online.  It
is very hustle free.  One of their apps is
IL Care.  If you go there and upload all your
documents, your
claim is settled.  HDFC Ergo is
also very easy for them.  If you
create a PDF of all the documents along with the
claim form and send it to the email ID care
@HDCO, your claim gets settled.
Tata AIGP is online.
Your claim is also settled through their app and link.
Neeva
is very hassle free of BPA.  If you submit all the documents by going to the link or their
app,
your claim gets settled.
SBI is offline.  Here you will have to
go to their branch with all the documents.
Then your claim will be settled.  And
similarly, if we talk about care,
both online and offline options
are available there.  Now let us come to the basic
features.  So first of all let us talk about the time and
how much amount of issue you have to
take for your health insurance policy.
I have made an exclusive video on this also.
You can see it in my comment section or
in my description.  You will
get its link.  So IC lmbda Elevate has the
option starting from Rs 5 lakh to unlimited sums.  Now it is the era of unlimited, so the
problem has also been made unlimited.
HDFC Ag Optima Secure has
options available from ₹5 lakh to ₹3 crore.
Tata AIG Micare Select
Plan also has options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to Rs 3 crore.
They are taken here in Neevapa Reshore 2.0.  They
also have Reard 3.0.  Where there
is an option of unlimited sum assured.  But here I am
talking about 2.0 only.  So you have options ranging from ₹5 lakh to
₹1 crore.
Options ranging from Rs 5 lakh to unlimited tenure include
SBI's Alpha plan which was launched in 2025
and Care's Ultimate Care
plan which is also a 2025 plan.
You get problems ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹1 crore.
Talking about entry age, there is
no maximum limit in all the plans now.
Minimum policy tenure is 18 years. Policies are available for 1 year,
2 years, 3 years, 4 years and 5 years.
Except HDFC and
Tata AIG, only 3
year options are available with Neevapa.  And if
we talk about SBI or ICC LBA, they have a
policy tenure of 5 years.  Where
you can get a discount.  There
are variants within these policies.  You're already
looking at my screen.  All these variants
are available.  Talking about family size, in
some of them there
is an option of two adult four kit and in some places the option of two adult three
kit is also available.  Let's talk about Rome Rent.
This
is an important aspect.  It becomes necessary to have a little discussion on this.
You can take single private AC room.
ICC Lombard's Elevate plan is
available if you do not take any add-ons.
What they have done here is that if you
take a policy for a single private AC room,
you get a discounted policy.  You
can upgrade it.  If you choose any room category,
you will have to pay a little extra premium.
If you
want to reduce the premium by downgrading, then you
can take the option of twin sharing room.  My
advice would be that you must have at least a single private
room.  There will be
no capping in HDFCO.  Tata AIG
is also the same.  There will be a single private AC room.
Upgrades can be downgraded.  No
capping is in Nivapa.  Single private AC
ROM is inside SBI Alpha.  Can be downgraded
and upgraded.
Any capping within the care will not remain within the Ultimate Care.  The
next slide is in front of you and this
slide also has many points in it.
For health insurance policy.
ICU, ICCU there is no capping.   There is
no co-payment in any of the policies.
Pre-hospitalization and post-
hospitalization are the most important points.
Pre means expenses before hospitalization and
post means expenses after coming from hospitalization, which are
quite expensive and
very expensive in case of critical illness.  These are expensive
medicines.  I even made a shot at cancer.
Medicines also have to be taken in the form of tablets at ₹4000 to ₹5000 and
three to four tablets have to be taken in a day.
So medicines worth lakhs of rupees per month
come free and post wise.  So the 90-
day and 180-day ICC are
inside Labard.  60 and 180 in HDFC Ergo
Optima Secure.  90 and 90 are
within Tata AIG's Medicare Select plan.
Rio will be 60 and 180 in two points.
60 and 90 and you can customize it
in SBI Alpha Plan.  They have
customized this plan to a great extent.   The
plan can be customized as per your needs and budget.  60
and 90 will be within Care's Ultimate Care Plan.
Day care treatment, modern
treatment, there is no capping supplement
in this plan.  Now let me move to the next slide
where there is ambulance, air
ambulance, no claim bonus, home
care, domiciliary and waiting periods for PED.  There
is no capping on road ambulances.  Except SBI Alpha,
look at the screen.  Starting from ₹300 and
multiple options are available depending on their variants.
Now
maximum companies have made air ambulance an addon and that
is also unnecessary, why pay premium
when you do not need it.  If you
live in a city where air
ambulance facility is not available
then there is no logic in paying for it.
It has been given as an add-on inside Lumbard i.e. in Elevate.  HDFC Ergo will have
inbuilt hospitalization cover up to ₹5 lakh.  ₹5
lakh with Tata AIG medicare add on.  It is
built into Reo 2.0.  SBI
Alpha also has an add-on and will
also be available as an add-on within Care Health's Ultimate Care.
No Claim Bonus which is an inbuilt one.  Let
us talk about that first.  20%
yearly maximum 100% under Elevate plan
which will not be reduced in case of claim and will
also be increased in case of claim.  That means there is
no no claim bonus.  There is a loyalty bonus.   The
secure benefit in HDFC Ergo's Optima
Secure is 50% and maximum 100%, this also has
nothing to do with the claim.
You will get it even if there is a claim or not.
50% and maximum up to 100%.
Within Tata AIG's MediSelect plan.  Here you can also avail a discount of 1% on the premium.
If you do
not want to take the no claim bonus, you will
get a discount on the premium as a no claim bonus.   The
vapor ratio is close to 2.0.  Booster Plus
3x, 5x and 10x options are available.  You
can choose according to the variant.  Up
to 10X is within SBI Alpha.  That means you can
take up to 10 times.  Your choice is 1X,
2X, 3X, 4X, 5X, 6X, 8X, 9X and 10X. The
premium will be decided accordingly.
Or you can get a discount of 2.5%
on the premium.  50% and maximum 100%
ultimate care and reduction will not happen.  Home
care is domiciliary cover.  The waiting periods for PED are
36 months across all policies.  Can be
reduced.  Policy to
policy options are given.  Annual health
checkup is also a good option.
Companies have now added this also.
Take what you need.  No, if you don't need it, don't take it.
IC Lobavet is add on 5% on maximum
5000 listed tests only on cashless basis
to HDFCR per lakh maximum 15,000
on reimbursement basis
from the lab of your choice.  Documents have to be
sent to them.  Rebars are done.  The Nevapar Ratio 2.0 with policy year add on of 1% of
the sum assured up to a maximum of Rs. 25,000
is listed here.  It is inbuilt.  There will be
no option of add on, it will be available only with add on in SBI Alpha
and if we talk about Care Ultimate Care, then
alternative treatment with add on will be listed there also, which we
also call AYUSH, it is now being covered in all the policies as per the
regulatory guidelines,
except for one or two policies, maternity cover is there in all the other policies and
this add on will be there in all the policies, 10% of the basic sum
assured maximum 1 lakh after two years, it will be there in
Lombard's Elevate plan,
you can take parenthood
in Optima Secure.  There you have the option
that the cover will be available only after 2 years.  How much
maternity cover do you need?  Cover
after 2 years 10% of the sum assured
maximum 1 lakh can be reduced for one year
You can avail this with add on under Tata AIG Select plan.  There is
no maternity in Nivapa Rio 2.0.  They have
separate maternity plans available.
SBI will remain in Alpha with the add on.  Where there are options, there will be
no maternity in multiple and ultimate care.  You will get
an individual separate video of all these six plans
on my channel.  If you
choose any of these plans, then you
must watch its separate exclusive video once.
After that you purchase that plan.
Consumables are available as add-ons in all policies.  Will be
inbuilt in Optima Secure.
Wellness program is available in almost all
policies.  Except SBI Alpha, there are
no deductible options even if I talk about Lumbard.  Neither is it in Ultimate Care.  All
other policies have the
option of deductible.  There is
a very good option to reduce the premium.
Where you can save a good amount of premium.  The
next slide has arrived
and this slide has special features.
All policies have some different
features.  See, health insurance
policy is basically the same that
hospital expenses are covered when you go to the hospital.
But to differentiate and
make the policy unique,
all the companies add some special features in it.
Well what is one nowadays?  Diabetes,
hypertension, hypotypedism are very common
diseases which have become very common in
our country.  So
companies have created an add-on for these diseases.  If
you pay a small additional premium for the add-on,
then it gets covered after 31 days or from
day one.  Almost all
policies have this rider.  If I
talk about SBI Alpha, it is not there.
You can reduce the cover of any PPD by spending one year there.
In all other policies, you can avail
instant cover and get cover for these diseases
from day one or after 31 days.   For example, if I
talk about Elevate, there are many
diseases there.  You are looking at my screen.
These will be covered after 31 days.  By
paying additional premium.  Same you have to
take in ABCD Writer Optima Secure.
In Select you have to take advance cover.
In Reo 2.0 you have to
take Disease Management Writer.
In SBI Alpha, you can reduce the PED cover to
one year.  And under the Care Ultimate
Care Plan, you can also take instant cover for
these diseases which you can
see on my screen.  Can be taken after 31st day.  There
is a power booster.  Inside the IC Siloma
Deliver Plan.  This is such a feature that
if you choose this plan then you have to
take it because what will happen in it is that
whatever sum assured you take the policy for, 10 lakh, 20 lakh,
it will keep increasing every year
up to base sum assured of 10 lakh, 20 lakh, 30
lakh, 40 lakh, that is, your policy will keep getting multipled throughout your life and will keep
beating inflation.
You have to take this add on if you
choose Elevate plan of IC, whereas there is
Plus Benefit in HDFC Ergo
where your sum assured gets increased twice by 50-50%.
Super Charge Bonus up
to five times under Tata AIG's Medicare
Select plan.  If you choose this plan then
you will have to take this add-on also.
Niva Buer Esho 2.0 has Booster
Plus.  Where your sum assured can increase up to 3X, 5X and 10X
depending on the variant.  In SBI Alpha, you can choose
from 1X to 10X as per your need and
budget.
Infinity Bonus Care Healthcare
is also included within the Ultimate Care plan.  Here also
your time savings increase throughout your life.
Facilities like Infinite Care, Infinite Advantage and Endless Cover are available.
With this add-on, you can make unlimited claims once in a lifetime whenever you want in HDFC Argo, ICC LBD Elevate and SBI Alpha plans.  But there is no lock the clock facility
Babu but this show is in 2.0.  Here
you get Lock the Clock in Platinum and Titanium.
Where your edge is
locked with the entry and
remains unlocked until you make a claim.
Premium does not increase
due to age.  But due to inflation, whenever they
increase the premium, your
premium also increases.  Care
Ultimate Care has premium payback.
If the policy runs continuously for 5 years without any claim, the
premium for the first year is
refunded.  Hospitalization for Two
Hours is now also available in Niva Bhupa.
Also available within TAo 2.0 and the Elevate plan.
Protect benefit is
provided by HDFCRO Optima Secure.  Your consumable
riders are inbuilt.  Covers all consumable
items.  Unlimited Restoration is
covered in all policies in Same Person Same Illness.  Now companies have also brought global cover.
You can get this facility in SBI's Alpha
plan with add-on cover.
Also, young family discount of 10%
is available.  If you buy the policy before 40 years of age,
you can avail Medics Excellent Plan under Tata AIG and
SBI Alpha with a lot of
covers.  There is companion cover,
convalescence cover, gym and sports
injury cover, OPD cover, and of course, a maternity plan.
Plan ahead.  If you
are unmarried and take Plan Ahead, you
can add your spouse guaranteed.  His
waiting period gets waived.  Also, there is
unlimited recharge in Ultimate Care.
Apart from that, you also get coverage during the grace period.  There
is a tenure multiplier.  That means, if you pay the premium for 3 years together,
you get 3 years of time cover from day one.
Similarly, these
are all the plans and these are the unique
features of all these plans.  Exclusive separate video of all these plans
is available on my channel Insurance Seva.
If you choose any of these plans, then first of all
watch that video.  After that
you select your plan.  So
now I am going to complete the video and
before completing it, let me
give you a highlight on its premiums.  I will take
25 lakhs at one edge.  I will take the age of 40 years
and I will take the age of 46 years.  See if the
premium suits you.  Let's
start with the ICC.  Age 40 years to Adult
to Kit Delhi NCR ₹37,923
you will have to pay.  Power Booster with No Room
Capping and Claim Protector.  A claim
protector is also necessary as
it covers consumable items.   If you
take 46 i.e. the second A slab,
then the premium will be Rs. 45887
for a sum assured of Rs. 25 lakhs in HDFCR
Optima Secure where we have
added unlimited restoration of 5% and the
premium is Rs. 40383 for 40 years to Adult
to Kit Delhi NCR, we change the slab there itself.  It comes at the
age of 46.
For a sum assured of ₹1 lakh, you will have to pay ₹45,464.
I
have this data of Tata AIG available for ₹1 lakh.
Here the age is 40 years.  Too adult to
kid.  You will have to pay ₹25,978.
Neev Now BoP Ratio
2.0 ₹25 Lakh Sum Assured for A Slab of 40 and 46
Two Adult Two Kit Delhi NCR
₹39595
and ₹5475
for 46 Years SBI Alpha ₹33649
for 40 years and
₹42,920 for 46 years.
Ultimate Care also
offers a 40 year old adult pay
to kit for ₹25 lakh where there is
no room capping and we have
added claim protector to it.  You will have to pay ₹376
for 40 years and
₹47561 for 46 years.
So these are the six plans,
I have
told you the basic things.  If you choose any plan, then
watch the individual separate video once.  If you have
any questions or queries, please
ask me in my comment box.  I will
meet you in my next video.  Till then
Jai Hind, Jai Bharat.